CHRISTOPHER KSIAZAK

SOFTWARF FNGINFFR

Summary

I'm a developer born and raised in El Paso, TX. I enjoy learning new technologies and applying that knowledge in designing and creating things that live on the web. For over a year, I attended Lambda School for Full Stack Web Development, and have worked with various distributed teams of different skill sets (ranging from Data Science to UX design, as well as other developers) and designed, researched, built, and iterated over several products. Afterwards, I started working with Ariana Suisse SA and was offered the opportunity of implementing a distributed service system using various Typescript technologies, of which I had to learn as needed. At the same time, I was offered my position back at E-Dealer Direct, in which through proper time management, I was able to complete both tasks as needed and without delay.

Before that, I focused on both the support side of a SaaS application as well as analytics. I mainly assisted in identifying ways that we could improve product design and issue resolution time to deliver better customer support to both end users and clients.

Employment

E-Dealer Direct Software Engineer

El Paso, TX July 2020 to Current

As life semi-returns to normal due to the current COVID-19 situation, I was asked to return to my position at E-Dealer Direct. In my current role, I operate both across the full stack and mobile development. My typically day to day technologies in use are React, React Native, Redux, SCSS, And Ruby on Rails. I lead product team discussions, and push out updates in a regular and timely manner, while both taking feedback on the current release and working on the next.

Ariana Suisse SA **Software Engineer (Contract)**

Remote May 2020 to Feb. 2021

In my partnership with Ariana Suisse, I'm the lead developer on creating a multi-tenant, distributed system using React (& React Native), GraphQL, Apollo Federation, Styled Components, Typescript, Elasticsearch, and various AWS services. Through discussions with clients, I continually create new features or reiterate on old ones. This is done completely remote across global time zones.

E-Dealer Direct

Software Engineer

El Paso, TX Mar. 2020 to Apr. 2020

Although not long, I joined E-Dealer Direct and served as part of the core engineering team. In my time there, I contributed to stack discussions in an agile environment, created wireframes and mockups using Figma, and planned and developed new features using React, Redux, SCSS, Javascript, and Ruby on Rails. Unfortunately, due to COVID-19, I was made redundant.

C3i Solutions

Project Coordinator

El Paso, TX Mar. 2017 to Current

- Worked in conjunction with our client, Castlight Health, across several time zones
- Transitioned our program through several of our client's product launches
- Maintained knowledge base with current issues
- Triaged bug reports to appropriate engineering teams
- Made data driven decisions through various reports from Salesforce and JIRA
- Analyzed flat files and API requests from Anthem

Projects

Ksiazak.dev is my personal portfolio page and where I typically go to test out new technologies. The current iteration is built using Nextjs, Styled Components, and MDX. I'm using a particle generator for the heading and Styled Components for the overall page styles.

Airbnb Optimal Pricing API

I was the sole backend developer and built this API using Nodejs/express. This product is meant for Airbnb users wanting to list their properties in Berlin and provides you with the optimal price for the area based on several factors. I worked with our data science, as well as our front end React team on API specifications and data design.

Songsight was built to help you find new songs based on songs you already love. For this application, I served as part of the front end team and worked alongside 3 other developers, a back end team, and a data science team. The frontend was built using React, React-Router, Redux, and Grommet for styling.

Contact

- cksiazak@gmail.com
- ksiazak.dev
- **(915) 253-8705**
- **♀** El Paso. Texas
- in cksiazak
- C cksiazak

Education

Lambda School

Apr. 2019 to June 2020

Skills

WEB DEVELOPMENT

CSS (LESS/SASS)

Javascript/Typescript

React

Redux

Node

SOL

Ruby on Rails

GraphOL

React Native

REPORTING, DOCUMENTATION, AND ANALYTICS

JIRA

Tableau

Confluence

Datadog

Salesforce